A Register of the Elena Iur'evna Iavorskaia Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Elena Iur'evna Iavorskaia Papers
1882-1970
2008C82
Iavorskaia, Elena Iur'evna
1 microfilm reel (0.15 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
These papers contain the family files of Elena Iur'evna Iavorskaia, a Russian émigré, who lived in Switzerland after the Russian revolution, and include educational documents, genealogical files, and various certificates.
Administrative Information
Access
The collection is open for research
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2008
Alternative Forms of Material Available
A portion of the collection is available on Microfilm
Location of Original Materials
Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary, Jordanville, New York
Biography
1915 April 14 Born E. Iu. Naryshkina, Orel, Russia
1930-1933 College de Montreux, received Certifica d'Etudes
1969 October 10 Died, Montreux, Switzerland
Scope and Content of Collection
These papers contain the family files of Elena Iur'evna Iavorskaia, a Russian émigré, who lived in Switzerland after the Russian revolution, and include educational documents, genealogical files, and various certificates.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Holy Trinity Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register. Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into five series: Biographical file, Correspondence, Notes, Photographs, and Printed matter
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the online catalog.
Subjects
Iavorskii, Iu. A. 1873-1937.; Photographs.; Russian émigrés.
Collection Contents
- Biographical file, 1882-1970 and undated. (Box 1)
  Bibliography, biography, certificates, drawing, educational documents, family correspondence, financial documents, identification documents, medical documents, obituaries. Arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Certificates, 1915-1969. (Folder 1: 1)
    Includes certificates of birth and death
  - Commemoration book, undated (Folder 1: 2)
  - Educational documents, 1932-1933 (Folder 1: 3)
  - Family correspondence, 1956-1964 and undated (Folder 1: 4)
  - Family file
    - Iavorskaia, E. I., certificate of death, identification documents, 1946-1949 (Folder 1: 5)
    - Iavorskii, Iu. A., 1882-1937. (Folder 1: 6)
      Includes bibliography, biography, certificates of baptism, and death, and educational documents
    - Naryshkin, A. G., 1915-1921. (Folder 1: 7)
      Certificate of nobility, registration
    - Naryshkin, G. A. and S. V., 1915-1919. (Folder 1: 8)
      Certificates of death, marriage, nobility
  - Financial documents, 1946-1970 and undated (Folder 1: 9)
  - Genealogical file, 1970 and undated (Folder 1: 10)
  - Medical documents, 1957-1969 and undated (Folder 1: 11)
  - Obituaries, 1949-1970 and undated (Folder 1: 12)
  - Pencil drawing of Elena Iur'evna Iavorskaia by Archimandrite Kiprian (Pyzhov), 1946 (Folder 1: 13)
- Correspondence, 1938-1951 and undated.
  Cards and letters, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent
  - Unidentified, 1938-1951 and undated (Folder 1: 14)
  - Garshenin, K. P., 1948 (Folder 1: 15)
  - Kiprian (Pyzhov), Archimandrite, undated (Folder 1: 16)
  - Rozman, Mikhail, Reverend, undated (Folder 1: 17)
- Notes, undated (Folder 1: 18)
- Photographs, undated. (Folder 1: 19)
  Eight prints, family photographs
- Printed matter, undated. (Box-folder 2: 1-8)
  Clippings from various émigré newspapers relating to general topics, as well as religion, and Russian history and culture. Not filmed. Originals retained by Holy Trinity Seminary